const e="english",o=200,s=75,t=[{id:822,question:"The army officer said that more ...... would be needed to prosecute the war?",option:{a:"guerrilas",b:"guerrillas",c:"geurrilas",d:"geurrillas"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:26,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:823,question:"If one perseveres ....... will surely succeed?",option:{a:"she",b:"one",c:"he",d:"they"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:27,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:824,question:"Musa has lived here for five years but he does not seem able to get over the enormously........ and elaborate rules that govern the society?",option:{a:"adsurd",b:"bizarre",c:"fantastic",d:"inticate"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:28,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:825,question:"As election day draws near, the party looks ...... because many of its members have....... other parties?",option:{a:"successful / decleared for",b:" vulnerable / defected to",c:"cheerful / moved to",d:"cheerless / cross-carpeted from"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:29,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:826,question:"....... a motor cycle can be harmful ..... your health.",option:{a:"riding / for",b:"riding / to",c:"to ride / for",d:"to ride / with"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:30,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:827,question:"The future of the company is ...... though many seem .....about it?",option:{a:"okay / optimistic",b:"promising / nostalgic",c:"rosy / pessimistic",d:"dicy / unsatisfied"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:`The future of the company is promising though many seem  nostalgic about it?

Rosy; means promising or suggesting good fortune or happiness; hopeful.

pessimistic; means tending to see the worst aspect of things or believe that the worst will happen.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:31,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:828,question:"By this time next year, I ...... twenty years old?",option:{a:" would have been",b:"will be",c:"could have been",d:"will have been"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:32,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:829,question:"The new manager was responsible for the …….of the organization.",option:{a:"uplifting",b:"lifting",c:"uplift",d:"upliftment"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:33,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:830,question:"Ali has been cured of his amnesia, he no longer suffers from ...... ?",option:{a:"rounds of anxeity",b:"loss of memory",c:"pains in his arms",d:"bouts of malaria"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:34,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:831,question:"The operations of the bank ........ not ...... cottage and small-scale industries?",option:{a:"does /covered",b:"does / cover",c:" did / covered",d:"do /cover"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:35,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:832,question:"The members of the team agree ........ all the members of the contract?",option:{a:"by",b:"to",c:"on",d:"with"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:`with is a PREPOSITION accompanied by (another person or thing). in this context, it is used in indicating the manner or attitude in which a person does something.

The members of the team agree with all the members of the contract.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:36,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:833,question:"Whenever we have ....... we feel better?",option:{a:"a long good talk together",b:"a good long talk together",c:" together a long good talk",d:"together a good long talk"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:37,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:834,question:"The match gave the team a chance to show their ........?",option:{a:"worth",b:"position",c:"prowess",d:"mettle"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:38,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:835,question:"These ........ must have ........ the World Bank officials?",option:{a:"analyses / attract",b:"analyses / attracted",c:"analysis / attract",d:" analysis / attracted"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:39,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:836,question:"The members elected Baba ....... of the committee?",option:{a:"chairman",b:"their chairman",c:"to become chairman",d:" to be a chairman"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:40,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:837,question:"One advantage of the English language in Nigeria is that it puts everyone ........ a common ........ ?",option:{a:"at /equality",b:" on / footing",c:" in / standing",d:"in / advantage"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:41,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:838,question:"The officer described the comments as ........ because it was very amusing?",option:{a:"ludicrous",b:"dangerous",c:"sad",d:"libellous"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:42,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:839,question:"You are free to solicit ....... support from the board?",option:{a:" by financial",b:"for financial",c:"financial",d:"a financial"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:43,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:840,question:"The highly appreciative audience clapped ........ hands and showered ......... on the lecturer?",option:{a:"their /encomiums",b:"its / encomiums",c:"their / invectives",d:" its / invectives"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:44,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:841,question:"Despite all preparations, the wedding did not ....... ?",option:{a:"come along",b:"come off",c:" come on",d:"come up"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:45,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:842,question:"The quality of your questions which ....... always attracted attention ....... never been in doubt.",option:{a:"have / has",b:"have / have",c:"has / has",d:" has / have"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:`Have is both a verb and a noun used with a past participle to form the perfect, pluperfect, and future perfect tenses, and the conditional mood. In the the question, the verb ''attracted'' shows it's in past tense.

Has is a 3rd person singular present indicative of have. 

it therefore safe to say; ''The quality of your questions which have always attracted attention has never been in doubt.'' is correct`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:46,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:843,question:"He is ....... Kaduna ......... an official assignment?",option:{a:"in / on",b:"at / in",c:"at / for",d:" for / in"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:47,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:844,question:"We did not understand what the magistrate said about ........ and battery?",option:{a:"acid",b:"insult",c:"assault",d:"touching"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:48,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:845,question:"Didn't ......... draw your attention to the entry requirements?",option:{a:"anyone",b:"someone",c:"somebody",d:"everyone"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:49,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:846,question:"....... any problems, I shall travel to London tomorrow on a business trip?",option:{a:"in spite",b:"given",c:"in case of",d:"barring"},section:`<b>LEXIS, STRUCTUREAND ORAL FORMS
(Questions 26 to 75 carry 1 mark each)
In each of questions 26 to 50, fill each gap with the most appropriate option from the lists provided.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:50,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:847,question:"",option:{a:"rough",b:"dog",c:"cough",d:"rot"},section:"<b>In each of questions 51 to 53, choose the option that has a different vowel sound from the others.</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:`as usual, we will consider a list of possible pronunciations of all the options above and the one with different sound from the rest will be picked. 

rough----[rʌf]

dog----/dɒɡ/

cough---/kɒf/

rot----/rɒt/. From the outlined pronunciations, we can see that only ''rough'' has a different sound ''ʌ'' from the other options with ''ɒ''. `,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:51,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:848,question:"",option:{a:"tear (verb)",b:"hear",c:"weird",d:"mere"},section:"<b>In each of questions 51 to 53, choose the option that has a different vowel sound from the others.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:52,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:849,question:"",option:{a:"does",b:"flood",c:"world",d:"son"},section:"<b>In each of questions 51 to 53, choose the option that has a different vowel sound from the others.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"does /dʌz/, flood /flʌd/, world /wəːld/, son /sʌn/",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:53,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:850,question:"Bu<u>s</u>iness?",option:{a:"grace",b:"rice",c:"eyes",d:"sink"},section:"<b>In each of questions 54 to 56, choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the underlined letter(s).</b> ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:54,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:851,question:"cou<u>gh</u>? ",option:{a:"though",b:"thoroughly",c:"trophy",d:"of"},section:"<b>In each of questions 54 to 56, choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the underlined letter(s).</b> ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:55,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:852,question:"Preach<u>ed</u>?",option:{a:"question",b:"castle",c:"past",d:"lotion"},section:"<b>In each of questions 54 to 56, choose the option that has the same consonant sound as the one represented by the underlined letter(s).</b> ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:56,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:853,question:"",option:{a:"convenient",b:"madam",c:"embarrass",d:"contribute"},section:`<b>In each of questions 57 and 58, choose the word that has a
different stress pattern from the others.</b>`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:57,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:854,question:"",option:{a:"success",b:"suffer",c:"blackboard",d:"calendar"},section:`<b>In each of questions 57 and 58, choose the word that has a
different stress pattern from the others.</b>`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:58,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:855,question:`Practicing medicine is not as lucrative as many people <u>think</u>?
`,option:{a:"know",b:"understand",c:"consider",d:"assume"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:59,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:856,question:"He is a <u>stringer</u> for a newspaper?",option:{a:"a financier of",b:"an editor of",c:"a freelancer for",d:" a reporter for"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:60,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:857,question:"I wish the commander were less <u>adamant</u> about his proposed <u>reprisal</u> attack on the enemy?",option:{a:" sentimental about / rehearsed",b:"unyielding about / retailatory",c:"supportive of / retributive",d:"tolerant of / surprise"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:61,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:858,question:"Tortoises need cool climates and must have places where they can <u>hibernate</u>?",option:{a:"reproduce",b:"hide at night",c:"sleep deeply",d:"relax"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:62,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:859,question:"The manager made <u>disparaging</u> remarks about the retiring officer?",option:{a:"rude",b:"derogatory",c:"parochial",d:"cynical"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:63,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:860,question:"The man outran his wife when they heard the <u>eerie</u> sound?",option:{a:"scary",b:"hissing",c:"harsh",d:"loud"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:64,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:861,question:"Teachers of music believes in its <u>therapeutic</u> effect?",option:{a:"healing",b:"sound",c:"lyrical",d:"rhythmic"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:65,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:862,question:"Adigun's jokes are always <u>puerile</u>? ",option:{a:"amusing",b:"childish",c:"empty",d:"entertaining"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:66,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:863,question:"I wonder what will be left of his essay when the <u>extraneous</u> material is deleted?",option:{a:"superfluous",b:"erroneous",c:"relevant",d:"main"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:67,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:864,question:`His success may be described as a <u>Pyrrhic</u> victory?
`,option:{a:"costly",b:" a deserving victory",c:"an easy victory",d:"indecisive"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:68,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:865,question:"The teacher's apparent nonchalant attitude was <u>misconstrued</u> by his students?",option:{a:"condoned",b:"misrepresented",c:"misquoted",d:"misinterpreted"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:69,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:866,question:"They are considered to be legal <u>luminaries</u>",option:{a:"directors",b:"power",c:"experts",d:"practioners"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:70,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:867,question:"The Executive Secretary has just <u>assumed office</u>?",option:{a:"resumed work",b:"started work",c:"returned",d:" been sworn in"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:71,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:868,question:"The warming tribes have told been told to <u>parley</u> with each other?",option:{a:"observe a truce",b:"hold talks",c:" sign a treaty",d:"suspend hostilities"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:72,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:869,question:"Let us not indulge in <u>recrimination</u>?",option:{a:"indictment",b:"accusation",c:"counter-accusation",d:"unfounded allegation"},section:"<b>In each of questions 59 to 73, choose the option nearest in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:73,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:870,question:"Identify the word that has the stress on the first syllable.",option:{a:"export (noun)",b:"commute",c:"intend",d:" import (verb)"},section:`<b>In each of questions 74 and 75, identify the word that has the
stress on the first syllable.</b>`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:74,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:871,question:"Identify the word that has the stress on the first syllable.",option:{a:"dismiss",b:"comment",c:"intact",d:"confuse"},section:`<b>In each of questions 74 and 75, identify the word that has the
stress on the first syllable.</b>`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:`dismiss

comment is both a compound noun and verb. as a noun, the stress would be on the first syllable and for a verb, the stress would be on the second syllable. since it wasnt specified in the question as a verb, that means it is a noun. it would be stressed thus: COMment

words with prefix always have their stress on the second syllable. Dismiss, intact and confuse all have prefixes and would be stressed on the second sylle as:

disMISS

inTACT

conFUSE`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:75,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:872,question:"The organization is constantly in a state of flux?",option:{a:"There are perodic changes in the organization",b:"The organization is facing a difficult period",c:"The organization is experiencing good times",d:"The organization is moribund"},section:`<b>In each of questions 76 to 80, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:76,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:873,question:"His meteoric rise to fame surprise everyone?",option:{a:"His rise to fame was only temporary",b:"People were amazed at his rapid success",c:"He became successful very suddenly",d:"He rose to the top quite unexpectedly"},section:`<b>In each of questions 76 to 80, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:77,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:874,question:"The politician was pilloried by the press for his inflammatory remarks?",option:{a:"The politician was snubbed by the press for his remarks",b:"The politician was criticized by the press for his remarks",c:"The politician was closely questioned by the press for his remarks",d:"The politician was ridiculed by the press for his remarks"},section:`<b>In each of questions 76 to 80, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:`To transcribe the statement above, we first need to know the meaning of the various words used;

pilloried means to be attacked or ridiculed publicly. 

inflammatory (relating to speech or writing) arousing or intended to arouse angry or violent feelings. example "inflammatory remarks"

synonyms: provocative · provoking · inflaming  · inciting · agitating ·

option D best translate the statement.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:78,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:875,question:"After the successful operation, he recovered by leaps and bounds?",option:{a:"He got well very rapidly",b:"His well-bound wounds aided his recovery",c:"He did a lot of keep-fit exercises",d:" He used to jog regularly"},section:`<b>In each of questions 76 to 80, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:79,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:876,question:"Audu was taken bad in the middle of the night?",option:{a:"He was caught",b:"He was robbed",c:"He was ill",d:"He was drunk"},section:`<b>In each of questions 76 to 80, select the option that best explains the information conveyed in the sentence.</b>
`,image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:80,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:877,question:"He travelled ONLY 20 kilometres before his car stopped?",option:{a:"Did he travel only 20 kilometres after his car stopped?",b:"Did he travel exactly 20 kilometres before his car stopped?",c:"Did you walk only 20 kilometres before the vehicle stopped?",d:"Did he travel more than 20 kilometres before his car stopped?"},section:"<b>In each of questions 81 to 85, the word in capital letters has the emphatic stress. Choose the option that best fits the expression in the sentence.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:81,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:878,question:"The king RAN to the palace?",option:{a:"Where did the king run to?",b:" Did the king walk to the palace?",c:"Did the queen run to the palace?",d:"Who ran to the palace?"},section:"<b>In each of questions 81 to 85, the word in capital letters has the emphatic stress. Choose the option that best fits the expression in the sentence.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:82,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:879,question:"The man BOUGHT the newspaper.",option:{a:"Is this the newspaper which the man bought?",b:"Did the man read the newspaper?",c:"Who bought the newspaper?",d:"What did the man buy?"},section:"<b>In each of questions 81 to 85, the word in capital letters has the emphatic stress. Choose the option that best fits the expression in the sentence.</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:`In answering questions on emphatic stress, the correct answer is usually the one that contradicts the statement.

option A clearly state the newspaper was bought by the man

option B has emphasis on the word read

option C has its emphasis on the person who bought the paper

option D has its emphatic stress on what was bought (newspaper).  All the options except B has the emphasis of buying the newspaper. Therefore option B best explains the above statement.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:83,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:880,question:"The university has been TEMPORARILY closed.",option:{a:"Has the campus been permanantly closed?",b:"Has the university been permanantly open?",c:"Has the university been permanantly closed?",d:"Has the college been temporarily closed?"},section:"<b>In each of questions 81 to 85, the word in capital letters has the emphatic stress. Choose the option that best fits the expression in the sentence.</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`Emphatic stress may be used in a sentence to compare, connect, or clarify things. Usually emphatic stress singles out the word that the speaker considers the most important, and in this case even a function word may become stressed.

Emphatic stress is the placement of emphasis on a word in a sentence. In responding to questions on emphatic stress in examinations, interrogative sentences will be provided as options. The interrogative sentence that contradicts the emphasised word is the correct option.

example. John’s watch is made of GOLD.

The emphatic stress is on the word ‘gold’

Option:

(a) Is John’s watch made of silver?

(b) Whose watch is made of gold?

(c) What is made of gold?

(d) Is John’s necklace made of gold?

Option [A] is the correct answer because the word ‘silver’ contradicts the word ‘gold’ and the interrogative statement provides a chance to re-emphasise the word ‘gold’.

 Is John’s watch made of silver? No, it is not made of silver; it’s made of GOLD.`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:84,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:881,question:"My UNCLE retired from the police?",option:{a:" Did your brother resign from the police?",b:" Did your sister resign from the police?",c:"Did your uncle retire from the army",d:"Did your brother retire from the police?"},section:"<b>In each of questions 81 to 85, the word in capital letters has the emphatic stress. Choose the option that best fits the expression in the sentence.</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:85,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:882,question:"The witness <u>averred</u> that had seen Dosun at the scene of the crime?",option:{a:"argued",b:"confirmed",c:"denied",d:"affirmed"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:86,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:883,question:"The high cost of living these days calls for a lot of <u>frugality</u>?",option:{a:"extravagance",b:"economy",c:"recklessness",d:"prudence"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:87,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:884,question:"Tunde's reaction <u>underscores</u> the point I was making?",option:{a:"justifies",b:"emphasizes",c:"summarizes",d:"contradicts"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:88,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:885,question:`Everyone admired the manager's <u>adroit</u> handling of the crises in the company?
`,option:{a:"clever",b:"tactless",c:"skilful",d:"clumsy"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:89,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:886,question:"The principal took exception to the <u>ignoble</u> role the teacher played in the matter?",option:{a:"embarrassing",b:"honourable",c:"extraordinary",d:"dishonourable"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:90,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:887,question:"He is <u>notorious</u> for his drunkenness?",option:{a:"popular",b:"unknown",c:"well known",d:"renowned"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:91,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:888,question:"The chairman's conduct <u>redounds</u> to the image of the company?",option:{a:"assists in",b:"reflects on",c:"contributes",d:"detracts from"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:92,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:889,question:"Her <u>phlegmatic</u> temperament endears her to her friends?",option:{a:"stoic",b:"irritable",c:"lively",d:"cold"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:`hese are various meanings of phlegmatic

a. Having or suggesting a calm, sluggish temperament; unemotional or apathetic.

b. not easily excited to action or display of emotion; having a calm or apathetic temperament.. synonymes apathetic, stoic, cold-blooded, sluggish. Antonymes edgy, excitable.

LIVELY is therefore the opposite of phlegmatic from the options given above. it means to be;

a. Full of energy or alertness; vigorous or animated: a lively baby; lively eyes.

b. Characterized by much activity or excitement:`,examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:93,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:890,question:"The workers suddenly became <u>restive</u>?",option:{a:"fidgety",b:"disorderly",c:"submissive",d:"calm"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:94,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:891,question:"The governor's visit is an <u>unprecedented</u> event in the history of the social club?",option:{a:"a perfect",b:"a momentous",c:"an insignificant",d:" an unnecessary"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:95,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:892,question:"The athlete has unexpectedly become <u>indomitable</u>? ",option:{a:"weak",b:"disoriented",c:"unruly",d:"unconquerable"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:96,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:893,question:"The evidence the leader gave was <u>incontrovertible</u>?",option:{a:"indulbitable",b:"contestable",c:"practicable",d:"logical"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:97,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:894,question:`He gave an unsatisfactory excuse but the boss swallowed it <u>hook, line and sinker</u>?
`,option:{a:"with a pinch of salt",b:"completely",c:"entirely",d:"without mincing words"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:98,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:895,question:"The <u>hardline</u> posture of the labour leader has not helped matters?",option:{a:"compromising",b:"imposing",c:"uncompromising",d:"difficult"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:99,hasPassage:0,category:"others"},{id:896,question:"The President gave another <u>extemporaneous</u> speech last Friday?",option:{a:"unprepared",b:"fascinating",c:"planned",d:"unfavourable"},section:"<b>In each of questions 86 to 100, choose the option opposite in meaning to the underlined word(s).</b>",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002",questionNub:100,hasPassage:0,category:"others"}],a={subject:e,status:200,total:75,data:t};export{t as data,a as default,o as status,e as subject,s as total};
